Guide to the Arthur Davison Ficke Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1895-1959; Series II; 9.75; (25 boxes)
  - ARTHUR DAVISON FICKE
    - Novels
      - Mrs. Morton of Mexico
        - Chapters 1-10: working draft, typescript, original and carbon, corrected., [ca. 1939] (Box 22, Folder 696-710)
        - Chapters 11-12: working draft, typescript, original and carbon, corrected, [ca.1939] (Box 23, Folder 711-712)
        - Typescript, original, first complete draft, signed, bound, in a slipcase, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 713)
        - Typescript, original, final draft, signed, bound in a slipcase, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 714)
        - "Unconscious Symbolic Elements in Mrs. Morton of Mexico ": typescript, original, annotated by Arthur Davison Ficke, 1939 (Box 23a, Folder 715)
        - "Unconscious Symbolic Elements in Mrs. Morton of Mexico ": typescript, carbon, annotated by Arthur Davison Ficke, 1939 Aug 22 (Box 23a, Folder 716)
        - "Unconscious Symbolic Elements in Mrs. Morton of Mexico ": typescript, original, annotated by Gladys Brown Ficke, n.d. (Box 23a, Folder 717)
        - Contract (2 copies), 1939 (Box 23a, Folder 718)
        - Correspondence, 1939-43 (Box 23a, Folder 719-720)
        - Movie notes: typescript, n.d. (Box 23a, Folder 721)
        - Notes: typescript with photographs and clippings, 1939 (Box 23a, Folder 722)
        - Play sketches: typescript, original and carbon, corrected, 1939 (Box 23a, Folder 723)
        - Reviews, 1939 (Box 23a, Folder 724)
        - Reviews, in scrapbook, 1939-40 (Box 23a, Folder 724a)
        - Royalty statements, 1939-40 (Box 24, Folder 725)
        - Synopsis registration: Author's League of America, 1940 (Box 24, Folder 726)
      - "Spoodle Spinney, The Story of a Country House"
        - Chapters I-XI: typescript, original, corrected, working draft, [1928?] (Box 24, Folder 727-729)
        - Chapters XII-XVI: holograph, corrected, working draft, [1928?] (Box 24, Folder 730-731)
        - Notes: holograph and typescript, [1928?] (Box 24, Folder 732)
          With ALS to Eugene Boissevain from Libbie Breen, 1928 Jul 19.
      - "Strangers in San Esteban"
        - Chapters 1-13: typescript, original, corrected, early version, 1932 (Box 24, Folder 733-739)
        - Chapters 1-4: typescript, orignal, corrected, final draft, 1932 (Box 24, Folder 740-741)
        - Chapters 5-18: typescript, original, corrected, final draft, 1932 (Box 25, Folder 742-748)
      - "The War Memoirs of Colonel Walter": holograph and transcript, original, corrected (Box 25, Folder 749)
    - Plays
      - The Breaking of the Bonds
        - Holograph and typescript (Box 25, Folder 750)
        - Prefatory note for a Russian edition, typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 751)
      - "The Enchanter's Vengeance": typescript, original, corrected, [ca. 1894] (Box 25, Folder 752)
      - Mr. Faust
        - First and second plan, holograph, 1910-12 (Box 25, Folder 753)
        - Third plan: holograph, final draft, [ca. 1912]
        - First draft, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1914 Dec 18 (Box 25, Folder 754)
        - Playbills, 1921-22 (Box 25, Folder 755)
        - Publicity, 1921
        - Reviews, 1918-22 (Box 25, Folder 756)
      - "The Flower of the Foam": typescript, original, corrected, 1902-03 (Box 25, Folder 757)
      - "Guinevere": holograph, corrected, 1904 Jul-Aug (Box 25, Folder 758)
      - "The Lone Tree": typescript, carbon, corrected, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 759)
      - "Marie's Little Lamb": holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 25, Folder 760)
      - "Nocturne Opus 40": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 761)
      - The Road to the Mountain [The Lord of Asia]
        - Typescript, original, [first] working draft, corrected, 1929 Oct (Box 26, Folder 762)
        - [Second] working draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1930 Jan (Box 26, Folder 763)
        - Typescript, original, corrected, 1930 (Box 26, Folder 764)
        - Clipping, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 765)
        - Correspondence, 1929-30 (Box 26, Folder 766-767)
        - Record of copies, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 768)
        - Printers' bills, 1930 Mar (Box 26, Folder 769)
      - The Stair Landing
        - Revised draft, typescript, original, corrected, 1921 Feb (Box 26, Folder 770)
        - Review, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 771)
    - Books of Poetry
      - An April Elegy
        - "Archadian Nocturne": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 772)
        - "Portrait of Thedore Dreiser": correspondence, 1952-53 (Box 26, Folder 773)
        - Typescript, original, corrected, annotated Donald Evans, fourth draft, 1916 Apr (Box 26, Folder 774)
        - Reviews, 1917 (Box 26, Folder 775)
      - Christ in China
        - Outline: holograph, 1926 Jul (Box 26, Folder 776)
        - Typescript, original, corrected first draft, 1926 Jun 8-14
        - Revisions, holograph, [first draft?], [1926]
        - Typescript, original, corrected, second draft, 1926 Jul 30 (Box 26, Folder 779)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, third draft, [1926] (Box 26, Folder 780)
        - Printed version, corrected, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 781)
        - Correspondence, 1928 (Box 26, Folder 782)
      - [Collected Poems]: holograph, and typescript, original and carbon, annotated and collected, [1945?] (Box 26, Folder 783)
      - "Frail Jar for Sacred Wine"
        - "City Poems": printed version, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 784)
        - Holograph and typescript, annotated unidentified draft, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 785)
        - Typescript, original, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 786)
        - Typescript, original, annotated, 1945 Jul-Sept (Box 26, Folder 787)
        - Typescript, carbon, [final draft?], 1945 Jul (Box 26, Folder 788)
          With a note by Gladys Brown Ficke.
        - Typescript and printed version, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 789)
        - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 790)
      - The Happy Princess
        - "Italian Phantasy": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 791)
        - Holograph, corrected, 1905 Sep 2-7 (Box 27, Folder 792)
        - Holograph and typescript, corrected, [ca. 1905] (Box 27, Folder 793)
        - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 27, Folder 794)
        - Publicity, 1907 Aug (Box 27, Folder 795)
        - Reviews, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 796)
      - The Hell of the Good [by Edouard De Verb]
        - Printed version, 1930 (Box 27, Folder 797)
        - Printed version: typescript (2 copies), 1930 (Box 27, Folder 798)
          With notes by Gladys Brown Ficke.
        - Printed version: inscribed to Gladys Brown Ficke by ADF, 1931 (Box 27, Folder 799)
          With "A Rhymed Alphabet for a Perfectly Rhythemical Lady": typescript.
      - "Hymn to Venus": typescript, original corrected, with artwork by Arthur Davison Ficke, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 800)
      - "Islands of the Mist: A Sonnet Sequence"
        - Typescript, original, corrected, 1914 (Box 27, Folder 801)
        - Typescript, original, corrected., [1914] (Box 27, Folder 802)
          - With: ALS to Arthur Davison Ficke from unidentified, 1917 Sep, [1914]
      - The Man on the Hilltop
        - "Snowtime": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 803)
        - Reviews, 1914-16, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 804)
      - Mountain Against Mountain
        - "Prayer": printed version, 1927 Sep 24 (Box 27, Folder 805)
        - Reviews, 1929-30 (Box 27, Folder 806)
      - Out of Silence
        - "Peasant Before A Shrine" and "November Moon": printed version (Box 27, Folder 807)
        - "Possession (A Sonnet): holograph and typescript, original and carbon, corrected, five drafts, 1923 Mar (Box 27, Folder 808)
          With ALS Carl Van Vechten from ADF, 1924 Jan.
        - "Three Sonnets": printed version, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 809)
        - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 27, Folder 810)
        - Reviews, 1924 (Box 27, Folder 811)
      - "Pairs of Animal Friends": typescript, original, corrected, with sketches by Arthur Davison Ficke (Box 27, Folder 812)
      - "Poems for Stanhope Blunt Ficke": holograph, 1918 (Box 27, Folder 813)
      - The Secret and Other Poems
        - "Hospital": printed version, 1936 Apr (Box 27, Folder 814)
        - "The Secret": printed version, 1935 Dec 7 (Box 27, Folder 815)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, draft, 1934 Jul (Box 27, Folder 816)
        - Proof, corrected, 1936 (Box 27, Folder 817)
        - Contract, 1936 Jan 28 (Box 27, Folder 818)
        - Correspondence, 1935-51 (Box 27, Folder 819-820)
        - Reviews, 1924-37 (Box 27, Folder 821)
      - Selected Poems
        - "Nocturne in a Library": printed version, 1925 Sep (Box 28, Folder 822)
        - Announcement of new edition, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 823)
        - Correspondence, 1949-66 (Box 28, Folder 824)
        - Library of Congress: copyright, 1926, 1943 (Box 28, Folder 825)
        - Publicity material, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 826)
        - Reviews, 1926-27 (Box 28, Folder 827)
      - "Songs and Sonnets to the Beloved": holograph, 1906-11 (Box 28, Folder 828)
      - "Sonnets": typescript, original, corrected, 1904-15 (Box 28, Folder 829)
      - Sonnets of a Portrait Painter
        - "Sequence of Sonnets": printed version, 1922 Mar 7 (Box 28, Folder 830)
        - "Sonnets of a Portrait Painter": printed version, annotated and corrected by Arthur Davison Ficke, fragment (Box 28, Folder 831)
        - Holograph and typescript, corrected, 1913 Jan-Jun (Box 28, Folder 832)
          With TL to Dartmouth Library from Arthur Davison Ficke, 1939 May 25.
        - Correspondence, 1950-69 (Box 28, Folder 833)
        - Reviews, 1915-36 (Box 28, Folder 834-835)
      - Spectra
        - "Opus 421" and "Opus 422": printed version, 1923 (Box 28, Folder 836)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, signed by Arthur Davison Ficke and Witter Bynner, 1916 Mar 2 (Box 28, Folder 837)
          With rejected poems.
        - Correspondence, 1916-69 (Box 28, Folder 838-839)
        - Reviews, 1916-17 (Box 28, Folder 840)
        - Reviews, 1918-60, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 841-842)
        - "The Spectric School": Others magazine printed version, 1917 Jan (Box 29, Folder 843)
        - "The Spectric School of Poetry" by Anne Knish and Emanual Morgan: typescript, original, corrected, and typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 29, Folder 844)
        - "The Spectric School of Poetry" by Anne Knish and Emanual Morgan: printed version (Box 29, Folder 845)
      - Tumultuous Shore
        - "The Blue Heron": holograph, corrected, 1941 Aug 31 (Box 29, Folder 846)
        - "Counsel of the Hills": two drafts holograph, typescript, original, corrected, 1941 Jun 11 (Box 29, Folder 847)
        - "Cycle of Salvation": three drafts, holographs, typescript, original, corrected, 1941 Apr 10 (Box 29, Folder 848)
        - "Eben Wrought": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 849)
        - "Enigma": holograph, corrected, 1941 Oct 1 (Box 29, Folder 850)
        - "The First Painter": holograph, corrected, 1941 Jun 13 (Box 29, Folder 851)
        - "The Fisherman": typescript, carbon, corrected, 1941 Mar 3 (Box 29, Folder 852)
        - "The Hawk": first and second drafts, typescript, original, and carbon, corrected, [1933-35] (Box 29, Folder 853)
        - "Journey to Philmont": eleven drafts, typescript, original and carbon, 1941-42 (Box 29, Folder 854)
        - "The Last Renunciation": original draft, typescript, original, corrected., 1940 Jun (Box 29, Folder 855)
        - "Mountain Forest": typescript, carbon, revised draft, 1941 Aug 31 (Box 29, Folder 856)
        - "Naked Girl on Hilltop": three drafts, typescript, original and carbon, corrected, 1941 Jul 15 (Box 29, Folder 857)
        - "The Place of the Oaks": holograph, corrected, 1941 Aug 6 (Box 29, Folder 858)
        - "Poems inscribed on two Ancient Chinese landscape paintings": printed version, annotated, 1940 (Box 29, Folder 859)
        - "A Rock at Noonday": holograph, corrected, 1941 Jul 22 (Box 29, Folder 860)
        - "To a Young Man Entering the Army": first draft, typescript, carbon, 1941 Dec 21 (Box 29, Folder 861)
        - "The Young Recruit": four drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1941 Apr 2 (Box 29, Folder 862)
        - "Visit to a Museum": first and second drafts, typescript, original, corrected, 1940 Apr 13, 21 (Box 29, Folder 863)
        - "Beggar's Wallet": typescript, original and carbon, corrected, first draft, working draft, 1940 (Box 29, Folder 864)
        - "Beggar's Wallet": typescript, carbon, corrected, first draft, 1941 (Box 29, Folder 865)
        - Typescript, original, corrected, unidentified draft, [ca. 1940] (Box 29, Folder 866)
        - Final draft, working copy, typescript, original, corrected, 1941 Nov 2 (Box 29, Folder 867)
        - [No. 1-25]: holograph and typescript, original and carbon, corrected, first draft, with notes, 1942 May 14 (Box 29, Folder 868-873)
        - [No. 26-53]: holograph and typescript, original and carbon, corrected, first draft, with notes, 1942 May 14 (Box 30, Folder 874-878)
        - Setting typescript, original, corrected, 1942 (Box 30, Folder 879)
        - Early page proof, corrected, 1942 Jan (Box 30, Folder 880)
        - Intermediate page proof, corrected, 1942 Jan
        - Later page proof, corrected, 1942 Feb
        - Blurbs, 1942 (Box 30, Folder 881)
        - Contract, 1941 Dec 16
        - Correspondence, 1941-48 (Box 30, Folder 882-883)
        - Fan mail, 1942 (Box 30, Folder 884)
        - Reviews, 1942, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 885)
      - "Twenty Rue Jacob: A Sonnet Sequence": typescript, original, annotated, [ca. 1917] (Box 30, Folder 886)
      - "Wild Honey": typescript, original, corrected, [ca. 1915] (Box 30, Folder 887)
    - Poetry
      - "Adeverising [Advertising] Costs America Five Billion Per Year": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 888)
      - "After Music by Jan Sibelius": typescript, carbon, annotated, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 889)
        With AN to Alan Devoe, n.d.
      - "America is Happy Tonight": printed version, 1939 Jan
      - "An Ode on the Occasion of a Party Given By Me Dedicating my Recently Acquired 'Encyclopedia Brittanica' to Household Use": typescript, carbon, corrected, 1929 (Box 30, Folder 890)
      - "Ancient Roman Inscription": printed version, 1932 Aug 31
      - "Antigone": typescript, original, corrected, [ca. 1903-04] (Box 30, Folder 891)
      - "The Author of the President's Speeches": typescript, original, corrected, [ca. 1946]
      - "Autumn Swallow": holograph, typescript, original, corrected, 1945 Oct 5 (Box 30, Folder 892)
      - "Ballad!!! Ballad!!! Ballad!!!," typescript carbon, annotated, n.d.
      - "The Ballad of Artie and Dannie": typescript, original, 1943 (Box 30, Folder 893)
      - "The Ballad of Mr. Moochow": holograph and typescript, original (Box 30, Folder 894)
      - "The Ballad of Mrs. Maloney, Mrs. Mahoney, Clarence, and Baby Nell": typescript, carbon, original, corrected (2 copies) (Box 30, Folder 895)
      - "The Ballad of the Parson's Son": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 896)
      - "Before Summer": typescript, original, [ca. 1904] (Box 30, Folder 897)
      - "Biggest Bill Thompson": typescript, carbon, and printed version, 1928 (Box 30, Folder 898)
      - "The Birds and Flowers of Hiroshige"; typescript, carbon (Box 30, Folder 899)
      - "The Bluest Blues": typescript, carbon, corrected, annotated, [sent to Floyd Dell], n.d. (Box 30, Folder 900)
      - "Borrow! Borrow! Borrow!": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 901)
      - "Bright Oak-Leaves in September": typescript, original, annotated, 1945
      - "Bucolic Epistle to the Romans": printed version, 1932
      - "The Bushar's Hymnal": holograph and typescript, original and carbon, with notes (Box 30, Folder 902)
      - "[Carmen Pringle]": fragments, typescript, original, corrected and annotated, [ca. 1933] (Box 30, Folder 903)
        With poem and note by Carmen Pringle, 1933 Apr 8.
      - "The Chrysanthemum Legend": typescript, carbon (Box 30, Folder 904)
      - "The Chrysanthemum Legend": printed version, 1933 (Box 30, Folder 905)
        With TLS to Gladys Brown Ficke from Horace J. McNeil, 1952 Apr 7.
      - "Class Poem": printed version (2 copies), 1904 (Box 30, Folder 906)
      - "Classical Nude": typescript, carbon., n.d. (Box 30, Folder 907)
      - "Complete Report of the Visit of Dr. Einstein to America": typescript, carbon, corrected, 1930 Dec 18 (Box 30, Folder 908)
        With printed version, n.d.
      - "Cosmic Cryptograms": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 909)
      - "Cosmograms": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 910)
      - "Creation": typescript, carbon, first draft, annotated, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 911)
      - "A Croquet Ballad": holograph, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 912)
      - "The Curtain Lifts": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 913)
      - "The Dandelion", "The Garden of Soami", and "The Legend of the Japanese Dwarf Pine Tree": typescript, carbon (Box 30, Folder 914)
        Written for the Hillsdale Garden Club.
      - "Day of Lamentation": song lyric, typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 915)
      - "Definitions and Maxims": holograph (Box 30, Folder 916)
      - "Doctor of Butterflies": printed version, 1922 Jul 22
      - "The Dogs of Hell": printed version, 1937 Apr
      - "Drab World": printed version, 1940 Oct 2
      - "Dream Sister"; "Pan Pipes"; and "Costume Du Ball": typescript, carbon, annotated, [ca. 1921] (Box 30, Folder 917)
      - "Elegy on Cheese": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 918)
      - "Escape to the Hills": printed version, [ca. 1933]
      - "The Face of Buddha": typescript, original, annotated by Gladys Brown Ficke, n.d.
      - "[Father and Lord]": typescript, original, corrected
      - "Father's Day"; typescript, original, corrected, 1940 (Box 30, Folder 919)
      - "For a Dead Poet": printed version, annotated (2 copies), 1928 Dec (Box 30, Folder 920)
      - "Fragments from The Book of Yak": typescript, original, annotated, 1940 (Box 31, Folder 921)
      - "The Garden of Soami": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 922)
      - "The German Dream": typescript, original, corrected, three drafts, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 923)
      - "The Gospel of the Trick-World Poet": typescript, original, 1929 Nov 7 (Box 31, Folder 924)
      - "Guingamoor": typescript, original, corrected, working draft, 1909, 1929 (Box 31, Folder 925)
      - "Hokusai": holograph, corrected and annotated, 1921 (Box 31, Folder 926)
      - "Highway": printed version, 1935 Sep 27 (Box 31, Folder 927)
      - "Hint to Memoir-Writers": printed version, 1936 Oct 24
      - "Homeland": printed version
      - "The Hour": printed version, 1940 Sep
      - "I Built Me a House: Words by Arthur Davison Ficke, Music by Alexander Bloch, on a Theme by Gladys Brown," manuscript (Box 31, Folder 927a)
      - "I Have Seen Beauties": printed version, 1914 Dec 2 (Box 31, Folder 928)
      - "In Praise of Games": printed version, 1937 Jan (Box 31, Folder 929)
      - "In the Night": holograph, corrected, 1941 Sep 23 (Box 31, Folder 930)
      - "Invitation to [Gladys]": holograph, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 931)
      - "The Iris Garden": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 932)
      - "Jean-Jacques Rosseau": printed version, 1932 Aug 7 (Box 31, Folder 933)
      - "Labor Day Picnic": typescript, original, with a note, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 934)
      - "Ladies of Taste": typescript, original, corrected, 1929 Jan 15 (Box 31, Folder 935)
      - "Legend of a Satyr": typescript, original, corrected (Box 31, Folder 936)
      - "The Liberal": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 937)
      - "The Liberation of Man": printed version, 1935 Sep 3
      - "Lines to a Certain Critic": printed version, 1936 Jul 14 (Box 31, Folder 938)
      - "Lines to a Poet Accompanying the Gift of a Handsome Blank Book...": printed version, annotated, 1923 Mar 5 (Box 31, Folder 939)
      - "Lines to Miss Brown and Mr. Devoe": typescript, original, corrected (Box 31, Folder 940)
      - "Lines Written Upon the Occasion of Miss Millay's Kindly Criticizing One of Mr. Ficke's Poems": holograph (Box 31, Folder 941)
      - "A Little Drink": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 942)
      - "Looking Into the Future": printed version, 1941 Jul 8 (Box 31, Folder 943)
      - "Lord William of the Isles": printed version, 1941 Jul 8
      - "A Lost Poetess": first draft, holograph, corrected, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 944)
      - "Lost Spring": song lyric, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 945)
      - "Man's Own Image": holograph, corrected, 1941 Jul 22 (Box 31, Folder 946)
      - "Many Monkeys": printed version, 1930 Apr 7
      - "Memorial for a Master Builder": printed version, 1937 (Box 31, Folder 947)
      - "Memory of George Sterling": printed version, 1933 Jul 3
      - "To Mr. Devoe, A Token of Thanks for the Loan of 'The Complete Works of Dr. Swift'": typescript, original, annotated, n.d.
      - "The Mothers": typescript, original, 1945 Sep 6 (Box 31, Folder 948)
      - "My Princess": correspondence, 1964-65 (Box 31, Folder 949)
      - "My True and Total Autobiography": typescript, original, 1945 Sep 8 (Box 31, Folder 950)
      - "Nannie and Warren": typescript, original [written with Witter Bynner], [ca. 1936] (Box 31, Folder 951)
      - "New England Countryside": printed version, 1932 May 20 (Box 31, Folder 952)
      - "A Newer Gospel": printed version, 1934 Jul 31
      - "News in Wartime": holograph, written to Alan Devoe, 1942 Feb 12 (Box 31, Folder 953)
      - "Note to a Friend": printed version, 1940 Mar 24 (Box 31, Folder 954)
      - Notebooks
        - Poems of Arthur Davison Ficke, Vol. I-VI, holograph, corrected, with sketches and indices, 1898-1902 (Box 31, Folder 955-959)
        - Poems of Arthur Davison Ficke, Vol. VI, holograph, corrected, with sketches and indices, 1902-04 (Box 32, Folder 960)
        - A Series of Sonnets: Vol. 7, holograph, corrected, 1903-04 (Box 32, Folder 961)
        - Poems: Vol. VIII-11: holograph, corrected, with indices, 1904-06 (Box 32, Folder 962-965)
        - Poems: Vol. 12: holograph, corrected, with an index, 1904-06 (Box 33, Folder 966)
        - Poems: Vol. 13, holograph, corrected, with an index, 1908-11 (Box 33, Folder 967)
        - Poems: Vol. 14, holograph, typescript, page proof, corrected, 1911-14 (Box 33, Folder 968)
        - Poems: Vol. 15, holograph, typescript, original and carbon, corrected, 1914-15 (Box 33, Folder 969)
        - Poems: Vol. 16, typescript, original and corrected, 1915-17 (Box 33, Folder 970)
        - Poems: Vol. 17, typescript, original, corrected, 1917-[29?] (Box 33, Folder 971)
        - Poems: [Vol. 18], typescript, original and carbon, corrected, 1929-41 (Box 34, Folder 972)
        - Poems: Index, holograph (Box 34, Folder 973)
      - "Nursery Rhymes": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 974)
      - "Oakdale Cemetery": typescript, original, corrected, 1945 Sep 24 (Box 34, Folder 975)
      - "Obscene Poetry for Miss G. Brown": holograph, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 976)
      - "Ode in Autumn": song lyric, typescript, original, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 977)
      - "Ode to the Four-Letter Words": typescript, original, signed, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 978)
      - "Oh Gee! I Wisht I was a Lunger": [by Edward Knish], printed version, 1929 (Box 34, Folder 979)
        With holograph note by Arthur Davison Ficke.
      - "On an Ancient Chinese Bronze": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 980)
      - "One of the Old Guard": printed version, 1941 Jun 7
      - "P.S. to Pome": holograph, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 981)
      - "Patriotic Song": holograph and typescript, corrected
      - "Petition": holograph, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 982)